SUNDAY
7:02 PM
57 HOURS INTO THE ROBBERY
The pharmacy has been robbed.
"They took the record books.
I have no idea how it’s happened.
Only you and I knew about it!"
"Do you know that moment
you tie loose ends
that you didn’t want to tie?
It’s painful, isn’t it?
You’re there with your long time partner
and you think:
'What a fucking bastard'."
I’m on my way there.
"Or: 'What a bitch'.
You refuse to believe it,
but you know there’s a betrayer.
And it can only be you or your partner.
And Ángel knew it wasn’t him.
Raquel was trying to find
an explanation to that,
but when explanations don’t come alone,
there’s always someone
willing to push you a bit."
I’m old-fashioned and still believe
in the good and bad guys.
And I am completely sure
that you are of the good ones.
Could you stand up for the detective?
Because I wouldn’t.
"Ángel thought nothing worse could happen,
but it could.
Sure it could.
When you hit rock bottom,
there’s still something
before the edge of the abyss."
Soil!
What's the matter?
What’s the matter, Moscow?
We have it!
We have it, mate!
"It wasn’t dark yet that Sunday evening,
when we were in a very euphoric mood.
We had found soil
and Nairobi had the printing presses
working at full capacity.
There was over 400 million euros.
We had sealed the entries
with explosives.
And had the feeling
of being inside a bunker.
It was our ten minutes of glory."
Who wants the sound of the sea?
This is like poetry for our ears.
This is the heart of the world
beating right here.
400 MILLION EUROS
Because we’re making it beat.
Because the world moves because of this.
What’s all this celebrating
you’re doing here? What’s the matter?
What’s wrong with you?
Hoorah!
"Undoubtedly, that was the happiest
moment for us inside there.
Then, we relaxed."
Don’t move.
Do you want to comb your hair?
Thank you.
Do you know how we say back home
"two men make love"?
We say "comb inside".
Sorry.
With all the medication
I have an upset stomach.
-Could I use the toilet?
-Sure, mate.
Thank you.
Jacinto.
Jacinto, it’s Arturo, can you hear me?
Mr Arturo.
You’re alive.
I was convinced you had been shot.
I didn’t sleep a wink.
We are in the basement with the boilers,
chained like dogs.
We’re locked up
with the four police officers.
We only come up here to use the toilet.
Listen up, Jacinto.
I’ve got a pair of scissors
and I can get hold of more tools.
Screwdrivers, a hand saw, I don’t know.
I can give them to you in two hours.
-Have you got a watch on you?
-Yes.
Make up any excuse.
Try to make them bring you here again,
in two hours,
from now on.
Remember, the second on the left.
I’ll leave them there.
What will we do
with a pair of scissors and a hand saw?
Those people have explosives,
M-16, and all sorts of things.
67 people’s lives are in your hands.
Believe me, it will work out fine, and
in a few hours no more nightmare for us.
All right.
Move, move.
Yes, yes, coming.
The pictures sent by the kidnappers
show explosives
connected to photoelectric cells.
They have been placed in all the entries,
even in the underground ventilation ducts.
-What kind of explosive are they using?
-The bomb squad think it’s C-4.
But I can see they’re more orange,
so we sent them out to the scientific
support branch to be verified.
-Who in the scientific branch?
-We sent them out to Alberto.
There’s no other inspector
in the scientific brunch
who does the same job as my ex-husband?
It was sent out to Alberto
because he’s the best.
It’s a direct order
from superintendent Sánchez.
I see.
-What do the scientific branch say it is?
-They think it’s P-4.
Very similar to C-4, British origin,
and that the connexion is perfect.
They’re making it difficult for us,
aren’t they?
"Alison!"
I think it’s time I had
a friendly chat with Alison Parker.
REPEATER ACTIVATED
Colonel.
There’s an incoming cell phone call
from inside the building.
Record it.
It’s from Jun Li, a hostage.
"It’s Aníbal Cortés.
What do you want?"
To help you, Aníbal.
In order to do so, we need
you to help us get inside the Fábrica
and get the hostages out
in the least aggressive way possible.
There’s plastic explosive
in all the entries.
Yes, coming in is no problem, but...
we need an ally.
"An ally who can tell us
where the robbers are at every minute."
I see, and why would I sell
my partners out to you?
They will tempt you with a better future,
a prison sentence reduction,
that in one or two years you’ll be out.
If you help us,
you’ll be eligible for parole,
a reduction in you prison sentence
to two years.
"You’ll have a new future ahead of you
by the age of 22. Think it over."
Divide and conquer, that’s the motto.
It worked for a small town in Italy
to take control of the whole world.
It worked for Napoleon later,
and now it’s working for the Police.
They’ll use the slightest contact
to tempt any of you.
After 48 hours inside
the pressure will start sinking in,
anguish, negativism.
And it will be then, when they’ll try
to aim for the weakest link.
"There isn’t weakness in us.
There is in those outside."
"It’s not too late, honey."
By the time they attempt to contact,
you’ll have committed six
or eight crimes, at least.
No judge can guarantee you
walking free, none.
Once inside, the only one
who can guarantee you being free
it’s me.
Aníbal, listen to me carefully.
"The judge guarantees you being free
in a very short time."
Okay, let’s square up
the numbers, inspector.
Let’s see, aggravated robbery:
from two to five years.
"Hostage taking and setting conditions
for the release of four escort
police officers: 40 years."
Hacking the alarm system, computer crime,
we’re talking about
six months up to two years.
Public order offence
for breaking in the Fábrica:
one to six years.
And with the hostages
It’s much more difficult.
67 hostages.
The law says that it can be from six up
to ten years for each kidnapping.
Then, it’s the point-blank shooting
at the police on the first day:
from six to eight years for each officer.
But they were wounded too,
which is an offence causing injury
"an aggravating circumstance
that adds eight years
for each injured police officer."
We are talking about,
if we have a tough judge,
723 years
the prosecution will ask for.
The shortest sentence you can be offered
by the judge and the prosecution, without
using the penal code as toilet paper...
"It’s 173 years.
Don’t let them fool you."
The penal code is the rules
of the game of any country.
No one can break them, no one.
There’s one thing
we can actually agree with.
The presidential pardon.
Tell him yes.
You want me to ask the president
for a presidential pardon?
No, I want you to ask the president
to be on TV
and in front of the whole Spain,
say that if any of the kidnappers
decide to cooperate to end this crisis,
the possibility of offering them
"a pardon in exchange
for their cooperation will be studied.
First, the president
will be in the news report."
-He’s bluffing.
-"After that, I’ll consider the option
-of being a fucking rat."
-Very good, we’ll do it.
But for that to happen we need
a gesture of goodwill from you.
Tell us the name of the Professor
and how many robbers there are inside.
I think we have to go along with him.
"Come on, Aníbal,
give me a name and a number,
and I can assure you
you will have a future again."
Okay.
A name and a number.
"Get a piece of paper and a pen”.
My bollocks 33!
What a son of a bitch.
Fuck.
Attention, we cut off all communication
with the Fábrica.
What the hell did you do?
You screwed up any chance
of buying us some more time.
They didn’t buy it, okay?
I could hear the bloody murmuring,
for fuck’s sake.
Let’s see, who do you think you are?
You had to execute, not decide.
Or change the plans, fuck.
And that murmuring thing,
what the heck is it?
He heard the conversation and if he says
she wasn’t buying it, it means she wasn’t.
We have been messing around
with the bloody inspector for some days.
So it’s not his fault, okay? Are we clear?
That’s right.
She wasn’t going to phone the president,
or the TV, or her fucking mother.
You and your things. You, assholes.
"Despite his great performance,
Río knew, the whole time,
he wanted to accept the deal,
freeze time and get out of there
as if nothing had happened."
Would you have liked
to accept the deal with the police?
You know that all this won’t end well,
don’t you?
Do you know what life imprisonment
without a possibility of parole is?
That’s what I’ll get.
I killed a security guy
and some months later I broke into here,
and I shot a police officer.
And you look so demure.
Do you think a judge will believe
in my reintegration?
No.
I trust the Professor.
I fully support him.
You didn’t answer me.
Would you have liked to accept?
Well, really...
what would happen if we got out of here?
Would we stay together?
Would you be trying to give me
my badge back all the time?
You're talking
about betraying your friends.
My friends?
My friends who have names of cities?
Tokyo, Berlin, Moscow, Denver...
My friends with cities' names
are ass-kicking.
And I’m going to tell you something.
You’d better hide away
if you accept the deal,
because if I see you,
I’ll shoot you in your temple.
I’ve just spoken to the security guard.
I saw him in the toilet.
He says that they are penned up,
11 security guards and 4 police officers.
They are our last chance.
I’m not hungry, thank you.
-Are you sure?
-Yes, thanks.
Our last chance,
how, if they are penned up?
We have to give them arms at all costs.
And also, obtain tools
and pass them on to them.
Which tools do you want to steal?
Drill bits, hammers, screws, anything.
You saw what I saw,
they’ve got and arsenal down there.
We have to take them
and leave them in the toilet.
Look, Pablo, I can’t do this on my own.
All right? I need your help.
When this Slavic gorilla
escorts me for a walk,
-I need you to distract him.
-Me?
Yes, he has treated my wound,
he doesn’t take his eyes off me,
he helps me to walk.
Then you distract him.
And I’ll steal the tools
and whatever is needed.
It’s over.
Arturo, relax.
Take care of your wound.
I’ll come later.
Come on, those in the tunnel, here.
-Those at the printing press, there.
-Don’t talk about the plan to anyone.
It’s only for us. The fewer we are,
the more chances we have to succeed.
We’ll help the others from outside.
Arturo, I’ll be back in a minute.
Come in.
And sit down.
Mercedes.
Hello.
I called you in to see
what can be done about your pupil.
She ran away and we found her
hiding inside the safety box.
Why do you think she’s so rebellious?
It might be, perhaps,
rebelliousness of virgins?
-What are you talking about, virgins?
-Nairobi.
We can see it in many species.
Virgins are rebellious,
because they haven’t been broken in.
I say this with all my respect.
It’s like what happens to mares,
not until they are broken in,
not until you ride them,
they can run off, kick someone,
they are completely unpredictable.
You must have heard
of that concept, haven’t you, miss?
How old were you when you lost
your virginity, Mercedes?
Mercedes.
There’s no problem, you can say it,
please, we’re here,
among friends.
Miss.
Well, eh...
I, you see, come from
a very small town in Soria.
When I was 24.
Good.
And weren’t you aware, before that,
of that virginal rebelliousness?
I don’t really know.
-Think about it.
-Maybe.
As a matter of fact, before losing it,
I ran away from home and went
to the Medinaceli festival, three times.
-I don’t know if that’s...
-That’s it.
Exactly that.
Here you are.
Intense "Volluto" with sugar.
Thank you.
Medinaceli festival.
And you, Alison?
Are you a virgin?
Yes.
So what?
I’m not scared of you
with those nutty speeches.
You won’t do anything to me, you know why?
Because I’m not just a hostage.
I’m a safe-conduct.
This is it.
The rebelliousness of the virgins,
here it is, no doubt.
Ariadna, darling, please, can you pass me
that small red folder?
-Coming.
-Sure.
Let’s see what we have here.
Your aunt Becky,
volunteer in a small village in Mali.
Here we have your cousin Elsie,
looking very beautiful in Kings College.
Brian, it’s the brainy one in the family,
in Wellington.
And here we have several photos,
whose? Your sister Lis, just next to you,
in La Moraleja,
she goes to the same school as you.
However, I think she doesn't have
your same temper.
A girl from your social status
I’m sure has no idea
how much a hit man costs to hire, do you?
We can find a decent one
for 30,000 euros.
However, to shoot your aunt in Africa
10,000 euros can arrange it, 10,000 euros.
Your family’s lives are in your hands.
Nairobi.
Move.
When I told you to make yourself heard,
I should have said
what’s most important
is to choose the right moment.
Call to monitor, Berlin.
-Everything well here, and in there?
-"Everything in order."
Brilliant, then the next phone call
in six hours.
Inspector,
the underground unit have found
oscillations on the seismograph.
They are working with heavy machinery.
Indeed, they’re building a tunnel.
We need to bring in a GPR, now.
See if we can find out
where they are building the bloody tunnel.
I’m on it.
Let’s see, listen all up.
Those who are not essential here
may leave.
Essential means
those who are doing something now.
The rest of you can go and have a rest.
And have a shower, please.
This is beginning to smell of deep police.
I rectify.
Please, can you all go out for a moment?
I have to relieve you from the case,
I’m sorry.
I think all this will be clarified,
but, right now, I can’t trust you.
You cannot trust me.
The thing is that you and I
knew about Toledo, Raquel.
You and I.
What the heck are you talking about?
I am not the betrayer.
So it’s only down to you.
What a nerve!
They knew we were entering the museum
wearing the masks
at the same time you knew it,
and they knew
we were going to the wreck yard,
and they knew about the fucking pharmacy.
Yes, it can’t be anything else, huh?
-What thing?
-Who knows? A phone call,
a telephone, a fucking microphone.
-Only you and I knew about the pharmacy.
-And you didn’t tell anyone, have you? No?
"Not even that weird guy from the café.
Did you say anything to him?
-What?
-To him, your shoulder to cry on.
A guy shows up here yesterday,
and you tell him about your whole life.
As if you were new in this."
And you don’t suspect him.
He’s been inside here, Raquel,
he’s been inside the tent.
Have you checked him out?
Because I have.
Have you done your bloody job?
He has a workshop, that fellow, nearby.
He says he makes cider.
And everything is covered by thin canvas,
who knows what he’ll be covering.
-Don’t tell me you have followed him.
-Yes, I’ve been following him.
He doesn’t do any cider or any bullocks.
He makes rubbish cider from a carton
and pours it into a cauldron.
And there’s rubbish all over,
fucking hell.
He has a car which is just scrap,
and sleeps in a bunk bed
surrounded by wheels and oil stains.
It smells like a chemist cooking meth
and I don’t know what the heck he cooks.
He is dodgy, Raquel, he is.
And you suspect me, I’m the only suspect.
Me, me, me!
How much will they pay you, one million?
Two?
Look here, Raquel.
Listen carefully.
Bugger off.
Suárez!
-Suárez!
-I can’t believe it.
Handcuff him and take him away.
Calm down, inspector.
That’s not the protocol.
-Yes, yes it is, Suárez, handcuff me.
-Bugger off the protocol.
-Handcuff me.
-Handcuff him and take him away.
If you want, I can call Internal Affairs,
but, for the time being,
no one is going to handcuff no one.
Raquel.
I’ve been 15 years with you.
With me? No.
You’ve been getting close to me
to see if I fall for you.
Always fucking Cercedilla in your mouth.
Always "I’m leaving Mari Carmen."
And your fucking womanizer’s jokes.
And now, that at last, I say no to you
it happens that Mr Pervert Pimpin here
has turned into a betrayer,
a betrayer.
What did you sell, Ángel?
Our friendship?
This operation?
Look here,
leave right now.
"Do you know
what ‘collateral damage’ means?
It’s a term coined during the war
in Vietnam by the American army,
when they didn’t have the guts
to talk clearly about killing civilians.
But it’s sometimes used
to take the blame off you,
like a boomerang.
And that was what was
about to happen to the Professor."
Hurry up.
Faster, faster, hurry.
Hurry, faster.
Take a couple of bags
and clean this crap.
Dinner is next.
I managed to steal a few things
from the tool box.
What things?
Some saw blades,
some screwdrivers, files.
Look.
What are you doing? Hide it away.
In 35 minutes,
ask to be escorted to the toilet.
Go in the second loo on the left.
Take the tools and you duct tape them
under the lid of the loo, inside.
They will get there in about 40 minutes,
All right?
It can’t be. Me? Me again?
I have stolen all the tools.
I’m loaded with scrap, fuck.
And you want to hand it to me here?
Do your part and I’ll do mine, mate.
"Raquel?
Is there anything the matter?
Are you all right?"
Well, I’m here alone and bored
in the café and...
and a little disappointed,
if I’m honest with you.
Excuse me, I don’t quite understand,
disappointed?
I was meeting up with someone for dinner.
My first dinner out in eight years
"with someone who wasn’t
my family, I mean.
But I think he stood me up."
And won’t it be
that you were 36 minutes early?
"It’s possible. The truth is I’m
a very impatient woman."
Sorry, Salva.
Excuse the joke, no...
I just wanted to make sure
you remembered about our date.
"The truth is
being stood up horrifies me."
I wouldn’t know what to do, how to get
out of here if you didn’t show up.
I guess I’d stay here
in my high heel shoes and on my own and...
drinking pints
until they told me to leave.
-Relentless.
-"No, embarrassed to death."
Don’t worry.
I’ll soon be with you
with those pints, in five minutes.
"See you very soon."
See you very soon.
"When you’re close to me,
I can’t even breathe."
Breathe then.
In nine months
you will not be able to breathe.
"It’s a joke, isn’t it?"
-Tell me it’s a joke.
-It’s not a joke.
-No, it’s not a joke.
-No.
Monica, I’m, technically,
I’m sterile.
"You must be Shiva,
the fertility goddess."
Shall I phone my wife, and the kids,
and we all go to celebrate it.
I told you that we had problems,
not that we were breaking up.
I brought you a menu,
you’ll be blown away.
Look, a sandwich that...
Well, I have eaten it a couple of times
and I’m still alive, so more or less...
Some biscuits, that...
I took the gluten free ones,
because I thought you might
-be gluten intolerant, as many people.
-Yes.
Perhaps, these better.
A chocolate pastry,
because I like them very much.
Ah, well, and...
Some sweets.
Do you want some?
"Hello, Raquel speaking.
I can’t answer your call right now.
If it’s urgent,
leave your message after the beep."
Raquel.
Raquel, it’s Ángel.
Listen, I’m asking you to reconsider.
Look, I can understand your rage.
I also overdid it, but...
Blimey, this is not the first row
we have had, you and I, is it?
Look...
I’m probably an asshole
or whatever you want, but...
but I’m not the mole.
I’m not the mole, for fuck’s sake.
You’ll screw my life up, Raquel.
You’ll screw my life up, damn it.
Give me a call.
What do you think about,
on the morning before a robbery?
You get up and, what’s on your mind?
I don’t know.
You get up there, at dawn,
"you smoke,
talk about nonsense."
What on earth are you doing
smoking so early?
Here we go, said the pot to the kettle.
-How are you?
-Fine.
And you?
Nothing extraordinary.
A lot of courage is needed.
I say it because I think
about that kind of things, you know?
About people who are on death row
or those guys that go in a rat hole,
shooting around.
-It’s not that bad.
-Yes.
It is. A very cowardly person
is telling you.
Look at me,
with a married man to avoid failure
or being dumped.
-You’re no coward.
-I am.
-You’re not.
-Yes, I am.
You stole a mobile
in the middle of a robbery.
You insisted on me shooting you
in your leg.
You stood firm before Berlin
who is crackers.
And you had the guts
to grab me by the neck and kiss me
and fuck me.
You need to have a lot of guts to bang
a loser wearing a Dali face mask.
You are Nikita, the secretary version.
Actually, the morning of the heist
I was scared to death.
"A fucking crazy thing."
-What?
-All this stuff, dad.
This guy...
He may look very clever, but...
-I don’t know, it’s crazy shit.
-No, it isn’t, no.
At least he knows what he’s talking about.
I started to doubt everything.
-I don’t know what I’m doing here.
-You’re with me.
But the thing is that everyone
is an expert in something.
So, the woman that fakes the banknotes.
You that...
You are a wizard at what you do, but I...
I haven’t done anything good in my life.
But he's a really good guy.
He told me he needed me and here I am,
meeting the most beautiful girl
in all this crazy stuff.
One minute.
"These are the tools we managed to steal.
Get undressed and tape them to your body
with insulating tape
to take them to the basement,
and untie yourselves.
Cut the ducts in the boilers room
and anything you can use as a weapon.
At 9 PM they’ll take your dinner down.
Take that chance
to disarm your captors and escape.
We’ll meet up at the warehouse,
hidden behind the coils.
I’ll try to take as many hostages
as possible without compromising the plan.
One second.
Out.
Thank goodness that I showed up.
As your date has stood you up...
Yes, yes.
I don’t know what would've happened to me
if you hadn’t showed up.
And your date,
were you particularly
interested in it or...?
No, not anymore.
What a shame.
Fine then, let’s see if I’m any good.
I’m sure you are.
Good, that makes me happy.
But I have something to confess
that we both are in danger, because...
if I have another one of these,
I may start to hum "muñeiras".
And we’ll have a problem.
I’m sure you look very funny.
When will we start addressing each other
less formally?
When you look at me under the table.
Come on, Salva.
Have a peep.
Look at me under the table.
I warn you that if you’re going to do
like in "Basic Instinct",
I might need something stronger,
because I’m a little conservative.
Salva, listen to me.
I don’t want you to make a scene here.
I’m quite sure
that you’re hiding something
in that workshop
where you supposedly make cider.
So either:
you willingly take me there
or we wait here
until I get a search warrant,
but I’m warning you
it could take a couple of hours.
So...
you choose.